[ Whistle Blows ]
[ Film Projector Whirring ]
♪ ♪ [ Orchestra : Swan Lake ]
[ Woman Laughs ]
♪ ♪ [ Continues ]
[ Ragged Breathing ]
[ Caws ]
[ Whimpers ]
[ Toe Shoes Clacking ]
[ Door Opens ]
[ Footsteps Departing ]
Mmm .
[ Bones Cracking ]
I had the craziest dream last night .
I was dancing the white swan .
It was different choreography though . It was more like the Bolshoi 's .
It was the prologue ...
when Rothbart casts his spell .
[ Cutlery Rattling ]
[ Gasps ] Look how pink . So pretty .
[ Together ] Pretty .
[ Both Chuckle ]
- You 're in a good mood . - Mm-hmm .
He promised to feature me more this season .
Well , he certainly should . You 've been there long enough ...
and you 're the most dedicated dancer in the company .
Up .
- What 's that ? - What ?
There .
Nothing .
Sure you don 't want me to come with you ?
You sweet girl .
[ Screech Of Train Brakes Echoes ]
[ Chattering ]
[ Man On Speaker ] Southbound 1 train to South Ferry .
Next stop , 59th Street .
[ Chattering ]
[ Woman ] Did you see Beth today ? I can 't believe she 's back .
Of course she 's back .
What ? She can 't take a hint ? The company 's broke . No one comes to see her anymore .
Uh , nobody actually comes to see ballet , full stop .
That 's not true . I heard the Royal had one of their best seasons yet .
He just needs to try something new . That 's all .
No . Someone new .
[ Chuckles ] Like who ?
Like someone who 's not approaching menopause .
It 's sad .
What 's sad ?
Beth 's such a beautiful dancer .
Yeah . So is my grandmother .
- [ Women Giggle ] - Well , Fonteyn danced into her 50s .
Yeah . We know .
Hey . Oh . Soloists ?
Great . [ Chuckles ] I fuckin ' missed my stop .
Had to hoof it all the way from 79th .
- [ Woman Whispering ] Who 's that ? - [ Woman # 2 ] It 's that girl from San Francisco .
Eh ?
♪ ♪ [ Piano ]
- ♪ ♪ [ Continues ] - [ Woman ] And up ...
two , three , four .
Good . One .
♪ ♪ [ Continues ]
Two , three , four .
Up .
Beautiful as always , Nina .
Relax .
And one , and two ...
and three , and four , and -
- ♪ ♪ [ Ends ] - Stop , John . One second .
Okay . Take position .
- And one , and two - - ♪ ♪ [ Resumes ]
And three , and up .
One , and two , and three , and four .
- How are you ? - Good . Thank you .
♪ ♪ [ Continues ]
We all know the story .
Virginal girl , pure and sweet ...
trapped in the body of a swan .
She desires freedom ...
but only true love can break the spell .
Her wish is nearly granted ...
in the form of a prince .
But before he can declare his love ...
her lustful twin , the black swan ...
tricks and seduces him .
Devastated ...
the white swan leaps off a cliff ...
killing herself ...
and in death ...
finds freedom .
♪ ♪ [ Stops ]
- Good morning , company . - [ All ] Good morning .
We open our season with Swan Lake .
Done to death , I know ...
but not like this .
We strip it down , make it visceral and real .
A new production needs a new Swan Queen .
A fresh face to present to the world .
But ...
which of you can embody both swans ?
The white and the black ?
All the soloists I tapped ...
go to your scheduled rehearsals this afternoon .
And the girls I didn 't tap ...
meet me in the principals ' studio at 5 : 00 .
Thank you .
[ Women Whispering ]
[ Ballet Mistress ] All right . Let 's go . Did we do left side ?
- [ Woman ] Yes , mistress . - Let 's hit it one more time .
♪ ♪ [ Resumes ]
♪ ♪ [ Humming ]
[ Bottle Clinks ]
[ Woman Grunts ]
- [ Woman Screams ] - [ Glass Shatters ]
Fuck ! Fuck !
[ Glass Shatters ]
What ?
[ Woman Shudders , Distorted ]
[ Broken Glass Clinks ]
♪ ♪ [ Piano ]
♪ ♪ [ Ends ]
If I was only casting the white swan , she 'd be yours .
But I 'm not .
Maestro . Odile 's coda , please .
Now show me your black swan , Nina .
[ Clears Throat ]
♪ ♪ [ Piano ]
Not so controlled . Seduce us .
Not just the prince , but the court , the audience , the entire world . Come on !
Your fouetteés are like a spider spinning a web . Attack it !
Attack it ! Come on !
[ Banging , Squeaking ]
[ Gasps ]
- [ Thuds ] - ♪ ♪ [ Ends ]
[ Director ] Well , good of you to join us .
- Sorry . - Girls , this is Lily ...
straight off the plane from San Francisco .
- She 's filling Rebecca 's old spot . - Hey .
- Get warmed up . - No , it 's okay . I 'm good .
Should I go again ?
No . Thanks , Nina . I 've seen enough .
Okay . Veronica . The white swan variation .
Come on , come on , come on , please .
All right . Maestro .
Two , three -
[ Retching ]
[ Toilet Flushes ]
[ Cell Phone Ringing ]
[ Ringing Stops ]
[ Cell Phone Snaps Shut ]
[ Distorted Laughter ]
[ Cell Phone Ringing ]
[ Mother ] So how 'd it go ?
You were late , so I called Susie in the office .
An audition . I can 't believe he just sprang that on you .
So ?
It was fine .
Just fine ? Oh .
- [ Sobbing ] - Oh , sweetheart .
Oh . Oh , you tell me about it .
[ Mother ] I know , Susie , but he just can 't expect these girls ...
to come back from a break and dance like Beth Maclntyre .
It 's completely unrealistic .
I mean , they can do the work , but they don 't have Beth 's magic .
[ Continues , Indistinct ]
She 's miserable , and it 's - [ Continues , Indistinct ]
[ Creaking , Distorted ]
- [ Cracks ] - [ Gasps ]
[ Groans ]
- Ow . - Nina ? Everything all right ?
I 'm fine !
[ Gasps ]
- [ Gasps ] - Oh . Shh .
Almost done .
You 're working yourself too hard .
We all have off days .
If that girl hadn 't barged in -
I 'm sure she didn 't mean to .
Remember when you first started ?
If I hadn 't taken you to each of your classes , you would have been completely lost .
I 'm gonna talk to him tomorrow . I 'm gonna tell him I finished it .
You don 't need to lie . It won 't convince him one way or the other .
Oh , sweetheart .
I know it 's disappointing .
And when you start getting older , there 's all this - [ Chuckles ]
ridiculous pressure .
God knows , I understand .
But it 's all right .
No matter what .
You 'll probably get to dance the pas de quatre again .
[ Chuckles ] That 's such a wonderful part .
♪ ♪ [ Music Box : " Dance Of The Swans " ]
Or maybe he 'll make you a big swan .
Either way , you 'll shine .
I know .
Everything will be better in the morning .
It always is .
♪ ♪ [ Continues ]
Sweet girl .
[ Director And Woman Speaking French ]
[ Woman ] Ciao .
- Yes , Nina ? - Do you have a minute ?
- If now 's not a good time , I can - - Now is perfect .
So ?
Um -
I just wanted to tell you that ...
I practiced the coda last night , and ... I finished .
I thought you should know .
Okay , Nina , listen . Honestly , I don 't care about your technique .
- You should know that by now . - Yeah , but yesterday -
No . Anyway , I 've already chosen Veronica .
So -
Sorry .
Okay . Thank you .
That 's it ? You 're not gonna try and change my mind ?
You must have thought it was possible .
Otherwise , what are you doing here all dolled up ?
I came to ask for the part .
[ Heartbeat , Distorted ]
Well ...
the truth is ...
when I look at you ...
all I see is the white swan .
Yes , you 're beautiful , fearful , fragile .
Ideal casting .
But the black swan ? It 's a hard fucking job to dance both .
[ Softly ] I can dance the black swan too .
Really ?
In four years , every time you dance ...
I see you obsess getting each and every move perfectly right ...
but I never see you lose yourself .
Ever .
All that discipline for what ?
- [ Whispers ] I just want to be perfect . - You what ?
I want to be perfect .
Perfection is not just about control .
It 's also about letting go .
Surprise yourself , so you can surprise the audience .
Transcendence .
And very few have it in them .
I think I do have it in -
[ Shouts ]
You bit me ?
I can - I can 't believe you bit me .
I 'm sorry .
Now , that fucking hurt .
- You were great . - Thanks .
[ Woman ] Yeah . Really . No . [ Continues , Indistinct ]
Yeah .
[ Chattering ]
[ Whispering ] What ? Why is she always staring at me ?
- [ Woman Giggles ] - [ Woman # 2 ] She 's obsessed with you .
[ Whispers ] Hey . It 's been posted .
Hey . It 's up .
Veronica .
Congratulations .
[ Excited Chattering ]
Hey !
Why would you say that ? Hmm ?
Your idea of some sick joke ?
What ?
Fuck you .
[ Woman Squeals ] Oh , my goodness !
[ Excited Chattering ]
Hey , Nina . Congratulations .
Congratulations .
Oh , Nina . Congratulations .
You were so beautiful at the audition . I knew you were gonna get it .
Congratulations .
- Congratulations . - Congratulations .
[ Line Ringing ]
- [ Mother ] Hello ? - Hi .
- What is it ? What 's wrong ? - I 'm fine .
- Um - - What is it ?
He picked me , Mommy .
- Did you hear me ? - For Swan Lake ?
- I 'm gonna be the new Swan Queen . - Oh , my God !
Well , um -
- I 'll be home soon . I just wanted to let you know . - I love you .
- I love you too . - Oh ! Please -
[ Stifled Sobs ]
[ Keys Jingling ]
Mom ?
Mom , are you in your room ?
[ Faint Laugh ]
[ Faint Shudder ]
[ Mother ] Nina . Are you home ?
[ Faucet Squeaks ]
Nina , when you get out , I 'm in the kitchen .
[ Mother ] Come on , sweetie .
My daughter , the Swan Queen .
It 's our favorite . Vanilla with strawberry filling .
Oh , Mom , not too big .
Oh , that 's way , way too much .
It 's a celebration . It 's just this once .
Mom , my stomach 's still in knots .
Fine .
Fine . Then it 's garbage .
No . Mom , don 't . I 'm sorry .
I 'm just -
I 'm just so proud of you .
That looks so yummy .
Mmm .
[ Both Giggling ]
- ♪ ♪ [ Piano ] - Smoother .
♪ ♪ [ Tempo Increases ]
[ Director ] Okay , okay . Thank you . Thank you .
Thank you , Nina .
It 's very nice .
But I knew the white swan wouldn 't be a problem .
The real work will be your metamorphosis into her evil twin .
And I know I saw a flash of her yesterday .
So , get ready to give me more of that bite .
Up ...
and -
[ Whispers ] All right .
Excellent .
That evil force is pulling you , that you can 't escape ...
that 's just like - [ Makes Noise ] out of your control .
So you 're - You sense it , you get aware of it more -
It 's taking me . It 's taking me .
A little bit more desperate .
Right . And you can maybe go up a little bit and then come down and then -
That 's it .
♪ ♪ [ Piano ]
[ Woman ] Three , four .
[ Continues , Indistinct ]
Oh , that 's beautiful . Step and a step . And -
Watch the way she moves .
Imprecise , but ...
effortless .
She 's not faking it .
[ Leader ] Gorgeous .
[ Groans ]
- Okay . That 's beautiful . - Sorry .
We 'll start again from the beginning .
[ Lily ] Okay .
Sorry .
[ Woman ] Welcome to the principals ' room .
You room with Beth from now on , so be considerate .
Thanks , Susie .
Those are for you , from Mr. Leroy .
They 're beautiful .
[ Inhales Deeply ]
[ Door Closes ]
♪ ♪ [ Classical ]
[ Chattering ]
- Come on . - I 'll be back in a second .
Let me come back to you , please .
Okay .
Let 's go .
♪ ♪ [ Continues ]
Ready to be thrown to the wolves ?
We need their cash , so , please , don 't forget to smile .
- Ladies and gentlemen , please , may I have your attention ? - ♪ ♪ [ Stops ]
- [ Woman ] Shh , shh . - Good evening .
Let me make this very important announcement .
You all have had the chance and the privilege ...
to be enchanted , transported ...
and even sometimes devastated by the performances of this true artist of our company .
She 's been a crucial inspiration to my work ...
a role model to all dancers , and even more than that ...
a deeply appreciated presence on our stage .
You all know who I 'm talking about .
Ladies and gentlemen , Beth Maclntyre .
[ Applause ]
But as we all know , every great career has to come to an end .
Beth is retiring at the end of the season .
[ Crowd Murmurs ]
She will be giving her farewell performance as Melpomene ...
the role she originated in my first ballet .
My little princess .
We honor you . You will be greatly missed and never forgotten .
But , as we bid adieu to one star ...
we welcome another .
We are opening our season with my new version of Swan Lake .
Taking the role of our new Swan Queen ...
the exquisite Nina Sayers .
[ Applause ]
[ Lily Giggling ]
- You 'll soon have - - Sorry .
the pleasure of seeing her perform , but right now , please ...
let 's raise a glass to all of us -
to Beth , to Nina ...
to beauty .
[ Patrons Chattering ]
[ Knocking ]
Just a second .
[ Groans Softly ]
- [ Knocking ] - Just a second .
[ Gasps ]
[ Knocking ]
[ Lily ] Come on . I 'm about to burst .
Hey . It 's you .
I don 't think we ever officially met . I 'm Lily .
Hi . Nina .
Yes . Our new Swan Queen .
- Here . Hold this ? - Yeah . Sure .
Oh , you must be so excited .
Oh . Are you freaking out ?
- Yeah . - Yeah ?
Oh . Oh , it 's okay .
Oh , I 'd be losing my mind .
Well , I should get back .
No . No , no . Come on . Stay . Keep me company .
Excuse me .
♪ ♪ [ Classical ]
There you are . Come on .
Hey . They tried to eat you alive , but here you are .
- You did well . - Really ?
Mm-hmm .
- Where are you going ? - Upper West Side .
Stop at my place for a drink . It 's on the way .
Thomas . You need to say hello to Karen Halloway .
A minute more of ass kissing , I 'll be back . Wait for me here . All right ?
Hello , Karen !
[ Gasps ]
Beth .
I 'm so sorry to hear you 're leaving the company .
Oh .
What 'd you do to get this role ?
Huh ?
He always said you were such a frigid little girl .
What did you do to make him change his mind ?
- Did you suck his cock ? - Not all of us have to .
You fucking whore .
You 're a fucking little whore .
Whoa , whoa , whoa , whoa . What 's going on here ?
Hey . Hey .
- I need to talk to you . - I think you 're drunk .
- I need to talk to you . - You should go home .
No ! Don 't you do that . Don 't you dismiss me like that .
Beth .
My little princess , please , hold it together .
- [ Beth ] I 'm coming by later . - Come on .
I have something for you . It 's a token of my appreciation .
- [ Thomas ] Right . - You make the most of it , Nina .
Don 't worry . It 's typical .
♪ ♪ [ Stereo : Classical ]
Please .
I thought it would be good to talk about the role . Ground us a little .
Yeah .
I don 't want there to be any boundaries between us .
- No . Me neither . - Good .
So ...
you got a boyfriend ?
No .
And you had many in the past ?
A few , but no one serious .
You 're not a virgin , are you ?
No .
Ah . So there 's nothing to be embarrassed about .
[ Clears Throat ]
And you enjoy making love ?
Excuse me ?
Oh , come on . Sex .
- Do you enjoy it ? - [ Nervous Chuckle ]
Well , we need to be able to talk about this .
I got a little homework assignment for you .
Go home and touch yourself .
Live a little .
Well , it 's late . Lots of work tomorrow .
The doorman will find a cab for you .
♪ ♪ [ Continues ]
Sounds like quite an evening .
I wish I could have been there .
- You know I asked . - I know you did . Susie told me .
- Guess he wanted you all to himself . - That 's not why .
[ Chuckles ] I don 't blame him .
Hmm .
- Where 'd you get these ? - They 're fake .
[ Chuckles ] Fooled me .
I can do it .
He must have been by your side all night .
Showing you off .
- Oh , Nina . - It 's just a rash .
Just a rash ? What are you talking about ?
It was worse a few days ago . It 's fine already .
- You 've been scratching yourself again . - No , I haven 't . Mom .
I thought you 'd outgrown this disgusting habit .
Jesus Christ . I thought you were done with this , Nina .
Shrugs . You 'll keep wearing the shrugs . Sit down .
- I have been . - You have the white one and the pink one ...
and that 'll hide it .
And then - And then I 'll dig out that - that expensive cover-up . We still have some .
No one will see it .
Mom , please .
It 's the role , isn 't it ? It 's all this pressure .
I - I knew it 'd be too much . I knew it .
- Ow . - Oh .
Are you all right ? You all right ?
It 'll be all right .
[ Exhales Deeply ]
[ Moaning ]
[ Panting ]
- ♪ ♪ [ Piano ] - [ Speaking French ]
Très bien , Veronica .
[ Speaking French ]
[ Door Opens ]
[ Sobbing ]
What happened ?
Beth 's in the hospital .
- She had an accident . - Oh , no .
[ Sobbing ]
- Beth ? - She 's really hurt .
[ Chattering ]
[ Nina ] What happened ?
She walked into the street and got hit by a car .
And you know what ?
I 'm almost sure she did it on purpose .
How do you know ?
Because everything Beth does comes from within ...
from some dark impulse .
I guess that 's what makes her so thrilling to watch .
So dangerous .
Even perfect at times .
But also so damn destructive .
Was it right after we saw her ?
Oh , no . Wait , wait , wait . This has nothing to do with you .
It 's not your problem , so don 't let yourself be distracted .
This is your moment , Nina .
Don 't let it go .
- [ Chattering ] - [ Phone Rings ]
[ Gasps ]
- [ Gasps ] - What are you doing ?
[ Sniffling ]
[ Mother Sobbing Softly ]
[ Sobbing ]
Nina ?
Sweetie , are you ready for me ?
And -
Come on . Forget about control , Nina . I want to see passion .
Come on .
Reach .
More ! You 're stiff . Stiff like a dead corpse . Let it go .
Let it go . Let it go .
And again .
It feels like you have , uh -
your diaphragm is in a bit of a ... contraction .
Okay .
[ Groans Softly ]
I want you to breathe into this hand . Breathe into this hand .
Breathe in , breathe in , breathe in . All the way .
- Good . And exhale . - [ Exhales Slowly ]
Oh .
Does it feel jammed in the front every time you plié ?
Sometimes . Not always .
[ Cracking ]
- One more pull . Okay ? - Okay .
- [ Cracks ] - [ Gasps ]
- Is that okay ? - Mm-hmm .
♪ ♪ [ Piano ]
David , can I ask you a question ?
Honestly , would you fuck that girl ?
[ Scoffs ]
No .
No one would .
Nina , your dancing is just as frigid -
[ Thomas ] Fuck ! [ Whistles ]
Oh !
[ Sighs ]
We 're still working here , please . Light . The lights !
Thank you .
Okay , guys , you can go .
Thanks for your patience . Na-da-da-da-da . You stay .
[ Chuckles ] You stay .
Have fun , you two .
Hey , oh .
Okay . Come here .
Come , come , come , come .
- [ Door Closes ] - I 'll be the prince .
♪ ♪ [ Humming ]
- [ Nina Breathing Heavily ] - ♪ ♪ [ Thomas Hums ]
Let it go . Let it go .
Feel my touch . Respond to it . Come on .
Open your mouth . Open your mouth .
Open it . Open it .
Open it .
[ Nina Moans ]
That was me seducing you ...
when it needs to be the other way around .
Please .
Who is that ?
Hey .
You okay ?
You can 't smoke in here .
Well , I won 't tell if you won 't .
So ...
big day 's getting closer and closer , huh ?
Well , I can 't wait . I think you 're gonna be amazing .
Thanks .
Come on .
So ...
do you want to talk about it ?
[ Sobs ] I just had a hard day .
Oh . Leroy playing a little too rough for you ?
Come on , Nina . He 's a prick .
He 's brilliant .
Sure . But it 's not like he 's all warm and fuzzy .
Well , you don 't know him .
Someone 's hot for teacher .
Oh . Come on . It 's okay . I don 't blame you .
- I should go home . - Oh , Nina , come on .
I 'm just playing around .
Nina .
[ Shudders ]
[ Woman Chuckles , Distorted ]
Sweetie ? What are you doing in there ?
♪ ♪ [ Piano , Violin ]
[ Nina Breathing Heavily ]
♪ ♪ [ Ends ]
Again .
♪ ♪ [ Resumes ]
♪ ♪ [ Ends ]
Again .
♪ ♪ [ Resumes ]
- ♪ ♪ [ Ends ] - Do you have any corrections ?
Lily told me that she saw you crying -
that you were very upset and that I should take it easy on you .
I didn 't tell her that .
- Maybe you need a little break , like a day or two . - Thomas -
- Or a month ? What do you think ? - She shouldn 't have said anything .
- No , you shouldn 't be whining in the first place . - I didn 't !
You could be brilliant , but you 're a coward .
- [ Whispers ] I 'm sorry . - Now stop saying that !
That 's exactly what I 'm talking about ! Stop being so fucking weak !
- Again ! - ♪ ♪ [ Resumes ]
[ Inhales , Exhales ]
[ Dancers Chattering ]
Lily ?
Oh , look who 's decided to grace us with her presence .
- I need to talk to you . - Okay .
- Now ! - Oww !
Shut up . Come on .
What 's up ?
You told Thomas about last night ?
Oh . Uh , yeah , I ran into him in the morning . He said you guys were having some trouble .
Why would he talk to you ?
Excuse me , Your Highness .
I told him you were working your ass off and that you 'll be great .
Well , you shouldn 't have .
[ Chuckles ] Okay .
[ Kissing Sound ]
[ Kissing ]
[ Kisses ]
[ Sucking Lips ]
Has he tried anything with you ?
He has a reputation .
[ Lighter Clicks ]
I have a right to be concerned , Nina .
You 've been staying late so many nights rehearsing .
I hope he isn 't taking advantage . That 's all .
- He 's not . - Good .
I just don 't want you to make the same mistake I did .
- Thanks . - [ Sighs ]
Not like that . I just mean as far as my career was concerned .
What career ?
The one I gave up to have you .
You were 28 .
So ?
And only in the -
Only what ?
- Nothing . - What ?
Nothing .
How 's your skin ?
It 's fine .
- Are we leaving it alone ? - Mm-hmm .
Let me see .
- Take off your shirt . - No .
[ Doorbell Rings ]
- Can I help you ? - [ Lily ] Is Nina around ?
Sorry . She 's not here .
- [ Door Lock Sets ] - Who was that ?
It was no one .
It was no one !
Hello ?
Hey .
What are you doing here ?
I just came by to apologize . You 're right . I should have never spoken to him about you .
- Sweetheart ? - Give me a second .
- Your dinner . - Mom , please !
Wow , she 's a trip . [ Chuckles ]
How do you know where I live ?
I have my ways .
[ Laughs ] Jesus , relax .
I got it from Susie in the office .
I feel really shitty about what I did , and I just want to make it up to you .
- So how about I take you out to dinner ? - I don 't think -
Okay , that 's fine . What about , um , drinks ?
Sweetie , you need to rest .
- Jesus . - Wait .
What are you doing ?
- Going out . - What ?
- Stairs . - Nina !
You 're on the stage tomorrow !
I can 't believe he calls her that . It 's so gross .
I think it 's sweet .
" Little princess " ? He probably calls every girl that .
No way . That 's just for Beth .
I bet he 'll be calling you " little princess " any day now .
I don 't know about that .
Oh , sure , he will . You just gotta let him lick your pussy .
[ Waiter ] Cheeseburger , extra bloody .
Mmm ! Danke schön .
Let me know if that 's juicy enough for you .
Oh , I will .
You got enough ... cheese ?
No , but you do .
Enjoy .
Okay .
Mmm .
Wanna spruce up ?
What ? I carry a spare .
In case I wake up somewhere unexpected .
So , how is he ?
Thomas .
I wouldn 't know .
- Oh , come on . - I really don 't want to talk about that .
Oh . Okay .
You really need to relax .
One for you , one for me .
- [ Case Snaps Shut ] - Oh , and don 't worry .
It 's pure . I promise . I brought it with me straight from San Francisco .
What is it ?
What , are you kidding ?
You 've never rolled ?
Oh , it 'll relax you .
It 'll loosen you up .
Let you see the night sky .
How long does it last ?
Couple hours , tops .
It 's okay .
Okay .
- ♪ ♪ [ Ambient , Muffled ] - [ Toilet Flushing ]
♪ ♪ [ Cell Phone Ringing : Swan Lake ]
♪ ♪ [ Cell Phone Snaps Shut , Ringing Stops ]
- [ Patrons Chattering ] - ♪ ♪ [ Continues ]
- I was - - That 's very sweet of you .
[ Lily ] Will you bring the drinks ?
[ Gasps ] Hey ! Hi !
- I thought maybe you and I could use a couple drinks . - I 'm gonna head out .
So , this is Tom and this is Jerry .
- Actually , it 's Andrew . - [ Man ] Tom .
Hi . Um , I have to go .
Oh , no , come on , you can 't go . I just got us some drinks .
I shouldn 't .
We 're on the stage tomorrow .
So , what are you gonna do ? Go home to Mommy ?
Hey . Come on . Live a little .
It 's just a couple hours , right ?
Tops .
- Hey . There you go . - Thank you .
- Cheers . - Cheers .
- You haven 't told me who you are . - Mmm . I 'm a dancer .
No , I mean your name .
Oh . Uh , Nina .
- So , are you two sisters ? - No .
Yes . Blood sisters .
We dance in the same company .
Ah , ballerinas . No wonder you two look alike .
You know , Tom and Jerry here are gay lovers .
- [ Tom ] Very funny . - I like to amuse myself .
- I 've never been to the ballet . - Oh , really ?
Oh , well , then you are definitely not gay .
- I mean , it 's kind of boring though , isn 't it ? - No , it 's not .
No . You know what , it 's just - It 's not for everyone .
You guys should come sometime . I can comp you tickets whenever you want .
- Yeah . - [ Lily ] Um -
Yeah , that would be ... neat . Thanks .
Okay , well , I think it is time for another round .
Bottoms up .
- Four , please . - So , what are you guys working on now ?
♪ ♪ [ Cell Phone Ringing : Swan Lake ]
I 'm sorry .
♪ ♪ [ Cell Phone Snaps Shut , Ringing Stops ]
- Uh , Swan Lake . - Okay .
Yeah ?
- You know it ? - No .
Not really . Heard of it .
What 's it about ?
Uh , it 's about a girl who gets turned into a swan ...
and she needs love to break the spell .
Okay .
But her prince falls for the wrong girl and -
[ Clears Throat ] so she kills herself .
So , a happy ending then .
It 's beautiful actually .
[ Andrew ] Like you .
Huh ?
I said , you 're beautiful .
That 's funny ?
Um , my hands are sweaty .
Hey .
- [ Sighing ] - Oh , hey .
It looks like someone might be rolling .
All right , come on . Come on . It 's time to go dance .
♪ ♪ [ Techno ]
[ Woman Cackling ]
- ♪ ♪ [ Pauses ] - [ Woman 's Voice ] Sweet girl . Sweet girl . Sweet girl .
[ Lily ] Hey ! Nina !
♪ ♪ [ Resumes ]
♪ ♪ [ Continues , Muffled ]
Hey , what the fuck ? Where you going ?
[ Car Horn Honking ]
Nina !
Where are you going ?
[ Gasps Softly ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Moaning ]
[ Woman Moans ]
- [ Lily Laughing ] - Shh !
Shh !
[ Giggling ]
- Do you have any idea what time it is ? - Mm-hmm .
Uh , late .
Where have you been ?
- To the moon and back . - [ Mouthing Words ]
- You 've been drinking . - Ding-ding-ding-ding-ding !
- What else ? - Hmm ?
What else have you been doing ?
Oh . You want to know their names ?
[ Laughs ]
You need to sleep this off .
- There were two . There was Tom and there was Jerry . - Be quiet , Nina !
And I fucked them both .
Shut your mouth !
- Don 't come in here ! - What 's this ?
It 's called privacy ! I 'm not 12 anymore !
- You 're not my Nina right now . - Leave me alone !
[ Both Moaning ]
Shh .
[ Sighs , Moans ]
[ Moaning Intensifies ]
[ Giggles ]
[ Sighs ]
Sweet girl .
[ Gasping ]
[ Nina ] Why didn 't you wake me up ?
I 'm moving out .
♪ ♪ [ Swan Lake ]
My music .
♪ ♪ [ Continues ]
Thomas , I am so sorry .
- Keep on going . - ♪ ♪ [ Continues ]
Go get warmed up .
- ♪ ♪ [ Ends ] - [ Applause ]
That was good .
Actually , really good .
Okay , let 's take 10 .
[ Chattering ]
Hey .
Look , he just wanted to work it and asked me to step in . Okay ?
- I overslept . - [ Laughs ] Oops .
Well , hey , at least you had a good time , right ?
- You put something in my drink . - Yeah .
And then you just took off in the morning ?
- In the morning ? - Yeah . You slept over .
Um ... no .
Unless your name is Tom , and you got a dick .
But we -
But we what , Nina ?
Wh - Did you have some sort of lezzie wet dream about me ?
- Stop . - Oh , my God !
Oh , my God ! You did ! You fantasized about me !
- Shut up ! - [ Gasps ] Was I good ?
♪ ♪ [ Resumes ]
[ Retching ]
[ Woman Laughs ]
♪ ♪ [ " Dance Of The Swans " ]
- [ Shattering ] - ♪ ♪ [ Stops ]
♪ ♪ [ Orchestra : Swan Lake ]
[ Thomas ] The final act !
Your final dance !
You tasted your dream , touched it ...
only to have it crushed .
Your heart is broken !
Wounded !
Your life force fading .
The blood drips .
The black swan stole your love !
There 's only one way to end the pain !
You 're not fearful , but filled with acceptance !
And you look down at Rothbart ...
and then at the prince ...
and then , yes , at the audience .
And then you jump !
Come on , go ahead . Jump . You 'll be fine . Jump !
[ Gasps ]
- ♪ ♪ [ Stops ] - [ Applause ]
Okay , everybody gets a drink of water .
Then it 's notes , hmm ?
[ Exhales ]
You lost weight . Take off your shrug , please .
Okay .
Very good .
[ Exhales ]
Face front . We 're almost done .
And that 's it .
Okay , you 're done . Thank you very much .
- [ Lily ] Georgina ? - Yes .
I 'm Lily . Thomas said I should come .
Yes , we have to get you measured for your Swan Queen costumes .
What 's she doing here ?
He made me your alternate .
Look , it 's just in case .
- Thomas . Thomas ! - I don 't want anybody -
- Thomas ! - Yes ?
It can 't be her . It can 't be her .
Okay , why don 't you just go ? I 'll catch up later .
- What 's going on ? - Lily .
You made her my alternate ?
Well , there 's always an alternate .
- Lily is the best choice . - No , but she wants my role .
- Every dancer in the world wants your role . - No , this is different .
She 's after me .
- She 's trying to replace me . - Nobody 's after you .
[ Sobbing ] No , please believe me .
Hey . Shh-shh-shh-shh .
I know it 's been a struggle .
[ Softly ] Yeah .
But you just had a breakthrough this morning .
Tomorrow 's yours .
Just give a great performance and you won 't have to worry about Lily or anybody else .
Now go home and rest .
From the vision again .
♪ ♪ [ Resumes ]
♪ ♪ [ Stops ]
What happened ?
I 've got a life .
Don 't work too hard . It 's your big day tomorrow .
[ Door Opens , Closes ]
[ Woman Laughs ]
[ Gasps ]
Hey .
I 'm still working in here .
Could you please turn the lights back on ?
[ Woman Laughs ]
Hello ?
[ Woman Laughing ]
[ Laughing Continues ]
[ Rustling , Thumping ]
[ Moaning , Gasping ]
[ Growling ]
[ Snarls ]
[ Whimpering , Gasping ]
[ Siren Blaring ]
[ Gasps ]
- What are you doing here ? - I 'm so sorry .
I 'm so sorry .
I know how it feels now .
She 's trying to replace me .
[ Sobbing ] What do I do ?
You stole my things ?
I was just trying to be perfect like you .
Perfect ?
No , I 'm not perfect .
I 'm nothing .
- Nothing ! - [ Gasping ]
Nothing ! Nothing !
- No ! - [ Groaning ]
[ Snarls ]
- Nothing ! Nothing ! - No !
Nothing ! Nothing !
[ Mother Sobbing ]
[ Sobbing Continues , Faint ]
[ Water Running ]
[ Voice Whispers ] Sweet girl .
[ Screams ]
[ Gasping , Whimpering ]
[ Gagging , Coughing ]
[ Mother Continues Sobbing , Faint ]
Mommy ?
[ Sobbing Intensifies ]
[ Voices Chattering ] Sweet girl . Sweet girl .
- It 's my turn . - It 's my turn .
It 's my turn .
[ Screaming ] Stop !
[ Voices Stop ]
What are you doing ?
Sweetie ?
- [ Bones Cracking ] - [ Gasping ]
Nina !
- Nina ! - Go away !
- [ Pounding ] - Open the door !
Go away !
- [ Cracking Continues ] - [ Groans ]
[ Pounding Continues ]
Open the door , Nina !
- [ Grunts ] - Nina !
- [ Grunting Continues ] - Nina !
- Get out ! - What 's wrong with you ?
- Get out ! - You 're sick !
- Get out ! Get out ! - You 're sick !
Nina ! [ Screaming ]
[ Screaming Stops ]
[ Crackling ]
[ Gasps ]
♪ ♪ [ Music Box : " Dance Of The Swans " ]
♪ ♪ [ Continues ]
[ Moans ]
Shh . It 's okay .
I 'm here .
You were scratching all night .
Where 's my clock ?
- Don 't worry about that . - What time is it ?
- Shh . - My show is tonight .
- No , no , no . - I have to - Ow .
No , don 't worry . I called the theater , and I told them you weren 't feeling well .
- I have to go . - No , no , lie down .
Let go of me .
You 're staying in here until you feel better .
Where is it ?
This role 's destroying you .
- Move . - Nina .
- Move ! - What happened to my sweet girl , huh ?
She 's gone !
[ Screams ] Ohh ! Nina !
Oh , Nina ! Oh , no ! Please !
- You 're not well ! - Let go of me !
- You can 't handle this ! - I can 't ?
I 'm the Swan Queen !
You 're the one who never left the corps .
Nina !
[ Woman Whispers ] It 's Nina .
[ Thomas ] I have complete confidence in you . Okay ?
Stay focused , and you 'll be fine . This is your moment .
- What are you doing here ? - Nina ?
- She was supposed to be sick ! - Wait , wait , wait . Give us a minute .
- Are you okay ? - I 'm fine .
Uh , Nina -
- Nina . - What ?
I 've already asked Lily .
Have you announced it ?
After Beth , do you really need another controversy ?
I 'm here , Thomas .
I 'm doing it .
The only person standing in your way is you .
It 's time to let her go .
Lose yourself .
- [ Knocking On Door ] - [ Man ] White swan , entrance in 10 .
[ Winces ]
[ Gasping ]
♪ ♪ [ Swan Lake ]
What are you doing ? You need to be upstage .
♪ ♪ [ Continues ]
[ Applause ]
[ Woman Laughing ]
♪ ♪ [ Continues ]
[ Laughs ]
[ Voices Chattering , Distorted ]
- ♪ ♪ [ Flourish ] - [ Applause ]
Hey .
We sucked !
Okay , Nina .
♪ ♪ [ Flourish ]
♪ ♪ [ " Dance Of The Swans " ]
- [ Wings Fluttering ] - [ Inhaling ]
[ Woman Laughing ]
- [ Shuddering ] - [ Grunts ]
- [ Gasps ] - [ Audience Gasping ]
[ Audience Murmuring ]
What the fuck ?
[ Stifled Sobbing ]
- Are you okay ? - Nina , are you okay ? What happened ?
[ Chattering ]
[ Audience Continues Murmuring ]
Can you tell me what the fuck happened ?
[ Both Speaking French ]
- It wasn 't my fault . He dropped me . - It 's a fucking disaster !
[ Thomas Speaking French ]
Rough start , huh ? Must have been pretty humiliating .
- Ohh . - Get out of my room .
See , I 'm just - I 'm worried about the next act .
I 'm just not sure you 're feeling up to it .
Stop . Please stop .
How about ...
I dance the black swan for you ?
Leave me alone !
[ Choking , Gagging ]
It 's my turn !
My turn ! My turn !
[ Grunting , Panting ] It 's my turn !
[ Whimpering ]
[ Sobbing ]
- [ Knocking ] - [ Man ] Black swan , places in five .
[ Gasping ]
♪ ♪ [ Fanfare ]
♪ ♪ [ Orchestra Continues ]
[ Wings Flapping ]
[ Snarling ]
[ Audience Cheering ]
Wow !
[ Moaning ]
- [ Moaning Continues ] - [ Feathers Rustling ]
♪ ♪ [ Continues ]
♪ ♪ [ Ends ]
[ Cheering , Applauding ]
[ Cheering , Applauding Continue ]
Get back out there ! Come on ! They want you -
[ Chuckles , Exhales ]
Great job . Fifteen to the last act .
[ Laughing ]
♪ ♪ [ Orchestra Continues ]
[ Muffled Tapping ]
- [ Gasps ] - Hey !
You were amazing .
Seriously , I know that things got a little messed up between us , but -
I mean , holy shit , you completely blew me away !
O - Okay , well , I guess , um , that 's it .
So I 'll - I 'll let you finish .
Meh .
♪ ♪ [ Continues ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Sobbing ]
♪ ♪ [ Continues ]
[ Wings Flapping ]
[ Audience Cheering , Applauding ]
[ Thomas ] Oh ! Can you hear them ?
They love you !
My little princess , I always knew you had it in you .
Come on . Let 's take your bow .
[ Gasps ]
Go get some help ! Go get some help !
- What did you do ? What did you do ? - ♪ ♪ [ Orchestra : Flourishes ]
- I felt it . - What ?
Perfect .
It was perfect .
- ♪ ♪ [ Ends ] - [ Audience Cheering , Applauding ]
[ Cheering , Applause Fading ]
[ Cheering , Applause Fade Out ]
[ Swans Calling ]
[ Wings Fluttering ]